Marietta, GA, United States eebesos@hotmail.com

Robert Sosebee

A loyal team manager, creative problem solver, and a polyglot software developer who thrives with getting individuals to work as a team. I get most enjoyment out of delivering successful products for both internal and external stakeholders. I have shipped products written in C#, Typescript, Javascript, Visual Basic, and even QBasic.

15 years as a software developer in the insurance industry. Full stack developer specializing in the Microsoft technology stack, cloud computing, and desktop development.

Technical Skills

Likes: C#, Git, Typescript, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, agile methodologies, Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence, Seq, Visual Basic

Experience

Development Team Manager - Assurance Systems, Inc.

**C#*, .net, wpf, silverlight, amazonec2, amazons3, typescript, javascript, html5, css, phantomjs, casperjs, mongodb, sql, visual basic, xml

**Nov 2014 - Current Curre

- Manage a team of 10 individuals consisting of 8 developers, an architect, and QA lead.
 Responsibilities include project management of all software projects we release.
- Project Scoping and Planning figuring out what needs to happen to get a project done and getting all the parts of the project into a workable state for development.
- Process Control getting tasks assigned out and completed in an efficient manner. From requirements through to QA and release.
- Release Management and Deployments coordinated released to QA and production and communicating these with all parties involved.
- Manage remote development and QA teams manage relationships with development team, QA, and tech support teams. Facilitate communication.
- Technology Monitoring and implementing use of productivity tools.
- Administration keeping track of work schedules, vacation time and job performance for the development team.
- Team Staffing Create job postings, interview, and hire/train new developers/QA staff.

Software Engineer - Assurance Systems, Inc. Feb 2001 - Nov 2014 c#, .net, wpf, silverlight, amazonec2, amazons3, typescript, javascript, phantomjs, casperjs, mongodb, sql, visual basic, btrieve, qbasic, xml, coypu

- Lead developer with rating modules, bridge APIs, credit web services, and screen scraping
 projects. Full stack web developer with Silverlight front end, C# and Visual Basic back end, and
 MongoDB database.
- Served as an expert with internal and external stakeholders on over 50 projects in many areas
 of our development stack.

- Led home rater project using Coypu, an open source tool, to scrape insurance carriers websites.
- As a junior developer, served as an integral part in converting QBasic to Visual Basic with not knowing either language well at the time.

Education

B.S. Computer Science - University of North Georgia

1996-2000

- Received academic and tennis scholarships
- Played singles and doubles on NAIA collegiate tennis team in,1996, 1997, and 1998.
- Member of Kappa Sigma National Fraternity

VFR Pilot (incomplete)- Bob Hughes Flight Academy at Peachtree Dekalb 1996

Volunteer/ Community

Tournament Director - Hall County Tennis

Sept 2010

- Directed a very successful 7 day long tennis tournament consisting of over 100 matches at 3 facilities. It was the biggest non USTA tournament held in Northeast Georgia
- Worked with sponsors to generate over \$100 worth of swag and expensive sweat wicking shirt for each entrant, and have 3 days of meals catered at the tournament. Entry fee was only \$25.
- Designed popular tournament logo.
- Persuaded several friends to volunteer their big screen TVs to have a Wii tennis tournament for spectators and players alike.

Driver - Transportation Committee - Atlanta BB&T Open Tennis Championship

July 2013

- This hard court tournament is the first of the US Open Series and is an ESPN televised event.
- Responsible for driving VIPs and professional tennis players to and from hotel, airport, restaurants, and practice courts.

Trail Builder - Southern Off Road Biking Association (SORBA)

Sept 2004 - Oct 2006

 Volunteered efforts in maintaining trails in North Georgia. Specifically with Carter's Lake, Chicope, and Pinhotti Trail systems.

Business Ambassador and Sponsorship Lead - American Cancer Society

Apr 2014 - Current

- Serve as the main point of contact and help teams meet and exceed their fundraising goals by utilizing tools and resources. Engage in the mission of ACS.
- As sponsorship lead: Retain and recruit volunteers to help with sponsor fundraising, recognition, and stewardship. Leverage kickoffs,

Tools

First Computer - Apple Macintosh

Favorite Editor - Visual Studio 2015 w/ Resharper and Sublime 3

Source Control - Git